Shiho Kanno c/o Daniel Öberg Kungsklippan 11, 4tr. 112 25 STOCKHOLM +46 (0)72-150 66 35 shiho.japanese@gmail.com



# Shiho Kanno

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a 29 year old Japanese girl who is a licensed high school and high school teacher. I am currently studying Swedish in order to be able to obtain a Swedish teacher's certificate.

I want to respect traditions and customs while still doing something new and creative. I often hear from children in my class that I am a person who is friendly and listens to their stories. And as a teacher I can organize and manage several tasks at the same time. In addition, I also have experience in how to teach fun and effective in Japanese and English since I worked as a teacher in Japan in these subjects for a few years. Finally, I would like to add that I did my internship at the Language Center as a Japanese assistant language teacher (via SIFA).

With that said, I hope I have aroused your curiosity!

#### **ERFARENHET**

Teacher — Japanska skolan, Stockholm

2017-04-01 ~

I have 5 classes every Saturday which is 45 minutes each. I teach math and Japanese. I have 13 students who are from 6 to 7 years old. In preparation for each lesson, I write teaching plans, correct homework, write summaries in the newsletter and consider how I can make my classes interesting and fun.

**Travel Assistant** — Tumlare Corporation Sweden AB, Stockholm

2019-05-01 ~

My tasks are to help Japanese tourist so that they can enjoy their stay in Sweden. I help them hotels check in, give some information, contact bus driver, duty free procedure and so on.

Store clerk (in fashion) — UNIQLO, Stockholm

2018-07-15 ~ 2018-08-15

While studying Swedish at Komvux, I worked at UNIQLO as an opening store clerk. The tasks I were handed was to work as a customer service position, cashier and so on. During my time

there, I learned the different way of the service, such as mixed Japanese and Swedish style and sales techniques.

Teacher — Kouhoku High School, Kanagawa Japan

2016-04-01 ~ 2016-11-30

I worked full-time as a teacher in intermediate level English in Yokohama city. I had 40 pupils in each class, a total of 160 pupils. In preparation for each lesson I wrote teaching-plans, corrected homework made handouts and scored tests. I was also a vice homeroom teacher and tennis club adviser as well during this time. I engaged in class management and school events planning too, but I had to quit the job early because of a joint decision to move to Sweden.

**Teacher** — Yokohama-sougou High School, Kanagawa Japan

2015-04-01 ~ 2016-03-31

I worked full-time I worked full-time as a teacher in intermediate level English in Yokohama city. I had 40 pupils in each class, a total of 160 pupils. In preparation for each lesson I wrote teaching-plans, corrected homework made handouts and scored tests. I was also a vice homeroom teacher and tennis club adviser as well during this time. I engaged in class management and school events planning too, but I had to quit the job early because of a joint decision to move to Sweden.

teaching novice level English in Yokohama city. The school was for students with special needs and built on a so-called "credit based system". This basically means that class hours varied a lot for the pupils as most of them attended school while working. Since many of the pupils had their own problems learning, I needed to put a lot of thought into the best way to teach English enjoyably while still efficiently. I was also a homeroom teacher for pupils who weren't able to graduate from school during the normal 3 years. Also, I was the adviser for the theatrical club. While teaching I also supported our principal as one of the members in the teaching committee of curriculum and instruction.

Teacher (Part-time) — Bunkyou Junior High School, Tokyo Japan

2014-05-01 ~ 2015-03-03

I had 12 classes a week. 4 of them was with an English native speaker.

**Teacher (Part-time)** — Tostuka High School, Kanagawa Japan

2014-04-01 ~ 2015-03-31

During evenings, I had 4 classes a week together with an English native speaker.

**Teacher (Internship)** — Ushioda Elementary School, Kanagawa Japan

2013-04-01 - 2014-03-03

The internship gave me a good insight into the roles of assistant teacher and main teacher. I acquired knowledge on how to deal with problems between children and how to teach enjoyably and efficiently, as well as techniques to attract the children's interest and draw out their knowledge in each subject. I also had to take care of violent children sometimes. My duties were to counsel the children, to support their studies with more.

Store clerk (in fashion) — Right-on, Kanagawa

2012-04-01 - 2014-03-31

While studying at university and working at Doutor I also worked at Right-on as a store clerk. I was working every day of the week in order to be able to pay my tuition fee for university. The tasks I were handed was to draw the customers curiosity and sell brand-clothes. I competed in sales towards other staff members as depending on the sales we could get extra salary. During my time there, I learned more communicative aspects, such as to coordinate sales and sales techniques. The customers were to a large part family.

Waitress — Doutor Coffee, Kanagawa

2010-04-01 - 2014-03-31

After school, and also during weekends I worked 5-6 hours at Doutor as a waitress. It was a very giving and unique experience for my first job. My tasks included everything from making drinks and sandwiches, helping customers to taking payments. The café was adjacent to a gasoline station and so we had to help customers with problems like car maintenance, car-washing and such things as well. It was a lot of responsibility.

### **EDUCATION**

International Studies + Teacher's programme — Bachelor of Arts vid Bunkyo University

2010-04-01 ~ 2014-03-01

Vid sidan av mina huvudstudier inom området internationella relationer avslutade jag lärarprogrammet också för att få en lärarlicens.

## LINGUISTIC KNOWLEDGE

- Japanska, modersmål
- Engelska, flytande
- Svenska, grundläggande (SVA grund 4)

## **OTHER**

- Har körkort (både svenskt och japanskt)
- Duktig på tennis (var ansvarig för en tennisklubb)
- Har ett certifikat inom abakusräkning (kulram)

## **REFERENCES/CERTIFICATES**

# Takahashi Tsutoo - Japanska Skolans rektor

Telefon: 08-640 33 13

E-post: Japanska.skolan@gmail.com

(9:  $00 \sim 17$ : 00 tisdag till fredag)

# Yokohama city Teacher's association

Telefon: +81-045-671 3246

E-post: ky-kyosyokujinji@cityyokohama.jp

(8: 45 ~ 17: 15 Japansk tid tillgänglig utom söndag, måndag och nationell helgdag)

## Kouichi Ano – Bunkyo Universitys professor

Telefon: +81-067-53 2111 (University)

+81-09-9814 5021 (Kouichi Ano's number)

E-post: k-ano@shonan.bunkyo.ac.jp

(8: 30 ~ 18: 30 Japansk tid tillgänglig utom söndag, måndag och nationell helgdag)

Fler referenser ges vid behov.